Guide to the Free to Dance Records, 1987-2004
American Dance Festival Archives Durham, N.C., USA
- Sound Recordings and Moving Images, 1994-2001 and undated, 78.75 linear feet (Box 20)
  - Paul Jefferson, Julia Foulkes, Dec. 21, 1999
    Sound Rolls: 111
    Audiocassettes: 82
    UB Number: 153
  - Julia Foulkes, Dec. 21, 1999
    Item Number: 7156
    Camera Rolls: 552-554
    Sound Rolls: 112
    Audiocassettes: 80
    UB Number: 154
  - John Perpener, Mar. 24, 2000
    Item Number: 7157
    Camera Rolls: 555-558
    Sound Rolls: 113
    UB Number: 155
  - John Perpener, Mar. 24, 2000
    Item Number: 7158
    Camera Rolls: 559-562
    Sound Rolls: 114
    UB Number: 156
  - Katherine Dunham Stills, Apr. 21, 1999
    Item Number: 369
    Camera Rolls: 563-565
    UB Number: 157
  - Sound Recordings, 1998-2000 and undated (Box 20)
    - Production DATs, 1998-2000 and undated
      - DATs corresponding to Sound Reels #21-31, 33-55, 57-87, 89-93, 95-114
      - Edna Guy V.O. Complete Session, July 5, 2000
      - Playback, June 10, 1998
      - Playback, June 15, 1998
      - Playback: D-Man in the Waters, undated (2 DATs)
      - Playback: Strange Fruit, undated
      - Unlabeled
    - DTRS DA-88 Recordings, undated
      - Five DTRS DA-88 tapes labeled X1 through X5
    - Production Audiocassettes (Box 21)
      - Numbered 1-83
        - 1 Closer to the Truth: Von Grona, Dec. 16, 1994
        - 2 Closer to the Truth: Henry Solomonoff, Dec. 16, 1994
        - 3-82 correspond to Sound Reels 3-5, 21-26, 28, 34-40, 42-43, 47-55, 57-75, 77, 79-82, 89-90, 85-100, 102-111
        - 83, 83A, 83B Joe Nash Pre-Interview, undated
      - Unnumbered
        - ADF "Free To Dance" Roll #101
        - ADF FTD Bill T. Jones, Dec. 9, 1998 (2 audiocassettes)
    - Long Playing Records (Box OS1)
      - House of Flowers, Harold Arlen, Columbia Special Products, 1973
      - Drum Rhythms of Cuba, Haiti, Brazil, Katherine Dunham, Audio Fidelity, 1950
        Audiocassette copy in box 21.
    - Sound Rolls (Box 54)
      - Five 7" reels of 1/4" audiotape, Sound Rolls 34-38
  - Moving Images, 1994-2001 and undated (Box 22)
    - Video, 1994-2001
      - Beta SP 6001-6004, 7002-7003
      - DVD 6001-6004, 7002-7003
      - Unnumbered Betas
        The following tapes appear to contain edited footage of complete versions of individual works. No complete works appear in Free to Dance; however, complete versions of Awassa Astrige/Ostrich, Barrelhouse Blues (excerpt), Strange Fruit, Mourner's Bench, Rainbow 'Round My Shoulder, and D-Man in the Waters (Section 1) are available on Dancing in the Light, a DVD commercially released in 2007.
        - Barrelhouse Blues, Choreography by Katherine Dunham, Performance by Cleo Parker Robinson Dance Ensemble, TRT 6:30
        - Children of the Passage (excerpts), Choreography by Donald McKayle and Ron Brown, Performance by Dayton Contemporary Dance Company
        - D-Man in the Waters, Performance by Bill T. Jones/Arnie Zane Dance Company, TRT 14:14
        - Mourner's Bench, Choreography by Talley Beatty, Performed by Jerome Stigler
        - Ostrich Dance, Choreography by Asadata Dafora, Performed by Garry Harris
        - Rainbow 'Round My Shoulder, Choreography by Donald McKayle, Performance by Dayton Contemporary Dance Company, TRT 17:38
        - The Stack-Up, Choreography by Talley Beatty, Performed by Dayton Contemporary Dance Company
      - D2 7002-7003 (Box 23)
      - Beta SP 7004-7015
      - VHS 7014
      - Beta SP 7016-7028 (Box 24)
      - DVD 7016-7028
      - VHS 7017-7018
      - Beta SP 7029-7036A (Box 25)
      - DVD 7029-7036A
      - Beta SP 7037-7048 (Box 26)
      - DVD 7037-7048
      - VHS 7039-7042
      - Beta SP 7049-7060 (Box 27)
      - DVD 7049-7060
      - Beta SP 7061-7072 (Box 28)
      - DVD 7061-7072
      - Beta SP 7073-7086 (Box 29)
      - DVD 7073-7086
      - Beta SP 7087-7100 (Box 30)
      - DVD 7087-7100
      - Beta SP 7101-7115 (Box 31)
      - DVD 7101-7115
      - Beta SP 7116-7126 (Box 32)
      - Beta SP dub 7126
      - DVD 7116-7120, 7122-7126
      - VHS 7123, 7125
      - Beta SP 7127-7137 (Box 33)
      - Beta SP dub 7133
      - DVD 7127-7137
      - Beta SP 7138-7147 (Box 34)
      - DVD 7138-7147
      - Beta SP 7148-7158, 369 (Box 35)
      - DVD 7148-7158
      - VHS 369
      - VHS 6001-6004, 7002-7005, 7007-7012, 7014-7029 (Box 36)
      - VHS 7030-7038, 7043-7044, 7046-7049, 7052-7065 (Box 37)
      - VHS 7066-7091 (Box 38)
      - VHS 7092-7114, 7116, 7122-7127 (Box 39)
      - VHS 7128-7130, 7132-7138, 7142-7158 (Box 40)
      - RESTRICTED. Screeners and other copies of video received from various repositories. (Box 41-47)
      - Dayton: Dayton Contemporary Dance Company, Feb. 6, 1999, Hi8 (Box 47)
      - Free to Dance Dayton #1 DCDC Sunday, Monday, Hi8
      - Free to Dance Tuesday #2 Dayton DCDC "Children", Hi8
      - Free to Dance DCDC: Ostrich, Mourner's Bench, Las Des, Rain, Barrelhouse, Hi8
      - Making of Free to Dance: Rainbow, Stack-Up, Ostrich, Mourner's Bench, Las Des, Hi8
      - Rehearsal Scenes, Donald McKayle and Ronald K. Brown with Dayton Contemporary Dance Company, Edited Sketches, VHS
      - Free to Dance Sampler, Sept. 18, 1998, Beta SP, VHS, DVCPro
      - Free to Dance Promo, June 1999, Beta SP, VHS
      - Free to Dance Promo, Sept. 1999, Beta SP
      - BAM Presentation, Jan. 17, 2000, Beta SP
      - Selects for Title Open, Music for Credits, Feb. 16, 2000, Beta SP
      - Rough Cut, Apr. 3, 2000, Beta SP
      - Final Cut, Apr. 13, 2000, Beta SP
      - Final Edit, Apr. 26, 2000, Beta SP
      - Show 2 Pick Up Narration, Blair Underwood, May 10, 2000, Beta SP
      - Narration Record with Blair, June 28, 2000, 4 Beta SP
      - Show #2 Titled/Mixed Protection Master, May 17, 2000, Beta SP (Box 48)
      - CR #OX10-OX11, June 30, 2000, Beta SP
      - Show #3 Generic Master/Split Audio, July 19, 2000, U-Matic
      - CR #OX12, July 20, 2000, Beta SP
      - Credit Sequence Beds for all 4 Programs, July 26, 2000, Beta SP
      - CR #OX30, Aug. 1, 2000, Beta SP
      - Show #1 What Do You Dance, Titled Master, Mixed Audio, Long Credits, Not for Broadcast, Sept. 12, 2000, Beta SP
      - Show #2 Steps Of The Gods, Titled Master, Mixed Audio, Long Credits, Not for Broadcast, Sept. 12, 2000, Beta SP
      - Show #3 Go For What You Know, Titled Master, Mixed Audio, Long Credits, Not for Broadcast, Sept. 12, 2000, Beta SP
      - Show #1 What Do You Dance, Titled Master, Mixed Audio, Sept. 12, 2000, Beta SP
      - Show #2 Steps Of The Gods, Titled Master, Mixed Audio, Sept. 12, 2000, Beta SP
      - Show #3 Go For What You Know, Titled Master, Mixed Audio, Sept. 12, 2000, Beta SP
      - Credit Roll for 3-Hour Broadcast, Sept. 12, 2000, DigiBeta (Box 49)
      - Thirteen/WNET: Free to Dance, April 27, 2001, 3 Beta SP
      - Thirteen/WNET: Free to Dance, April 27, 2001, 3 Beta SP
      - The American Dance Festival and the John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts in association with Thirteen/WNET New York: Free to Dance, 3 Beta SP
      - 3 Minute Promo, 4:45 Minute Promo, undated, Beta SP
      - 15 PBS Fillers, undated, VHS
      - Compilation Tapes #1-3, undated, 3 VHS (Box 50)
      - D-Man in the Waters Rough Cut GH Cut 2, Jan. 29, 2000, VHS
      - Edited Dance Sequences, undated, VHS
      - Free to Dance: Barrelhouse Blues, Ostrich Dance, D-Man in the Waters, Mourner's Bench, Rainbow Round My Shoulder, The Stack Up, Children of the Passage (Excerpts), Beta SP
      - Filler, 6 Teases, Opening Graphic, Mixed, Titled, undated, DigiBeta
      - Filler, 6 Teases, Open, Split, Pre-Mixed Audio, No Titles, undated, DigiBeta
      - Filler: The African Drum: The Beat Behind the Dance, undated, VHS
      - Sample Videotape for PBS, undated, VHS
      - Show 2 Narration, Tape 1, undated, Beta SP
      - Show 2 Narration, Tape 2, undated, Beta SP
      - Show 2 Reading for "Strange Fruit" Transfer from DAT, Beta SP
      - Tape 2 Unedited Dances: Etude, Strange Fruit, Levee Blues, Choros, undated, VHS
      - Trial Compilation, undated, 2 VHS
    - Camera Rolls, 1994-2001 (Box 51)
      - 60-67, A68-A75
      - A76-A93 (Box 52)
      - B68-B87 (Box 53)
      - B88-B91, 94-104 (Box 54)
      - 105-118 (Box 55)
      - 119-134 (Box 56)
      - 135-149 (Box 57)
      - 150-167 (Box 58)
      - 168-179 (Box 59)
      - 180-190 (Box 60)
      - 191-206 (Box 61)
      - 207-222 (Box 62)
      - 223-238 (Box 63)
      - 239-254 (Box 64)
      - 255-269 (Box 65)
      - 270-285 (Box 66)
      - 286-300 (Box 67)
      - 301-317 (Box 68)
      - 318-333 (Box 69)
      - 334-350 (Box 70)
      - 351-366 (Box 71)
      - 367-382 (Box 72)
      - 383-402 (Box 73)
      - 403-420 (Box 74)
      - 421-439 (Box 75)
      - 440-457 (Box 76)
      - 458-459, A460-A473 (Box 77)
      - A474-A475, B460-B475 (Box 78)
      - A476, 477-487 (Box 79)
      - 488-505 (Box 80)
      - 205-521 (Box 81)
      - 522-539 (Box 82)
      - 540-556 (Box 83)
      - 557-565, OX10-OX12, OX30, UN1 (Box 84)